<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A nonprofit-focused carbon offset and conservation project marketplace built on ServiceNow would:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Democratize access for small-scale conservation initiatives, amplifying their global reach.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Facilitate direct matching between donors and transparent, local projects, thus improving donor confidence and raising funds for climate-positive action.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Offer verifiable digital certificates and real-time dashboards to both project sponsors and contributors.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Support social safeguards and rights for Indigenous Peoples and local communities through transparent impact reporting, grievance mechanisms, and consent flows.</p>
</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>The voluntary carbon offset market is growing, but nonprofits and small community projects face significant barriers to participation: lack of standard digital infrastructure for listing high-quality projects, difficulty in matching donors to relevant causes, limited transparency in carbon credit certification, and complex reporting requirements. Trust issues around “greenwashing,” double-counting, and inequitable benefit-sharing—especially for Indigenous and local communities—further hinder impact and engagement. Many nature conservation projects lack a simple, digital way to show tangible progress and deliver verifiable certificates to donors, making the process opaque and underutilized.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Carbon Offset &amp; Nature Conservation Marketplace</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal solution is a digital marketplace on ServiceNow where:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Nonprofit and local project owners can list carbon offset/nature restoration projects with live metrics and evidence of impact.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Donors browse, contribute, and receive verified, blockchain-based certificates for their offsets.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Built-in automation validates project status (tree count, emission capture, etc.) and manages project-to-donor transparency.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Integration with external carbon registries and certification bodies (via API).</p>
</li><li>
<p>Secure, optionally blockchain-enabled certificate management.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Payment processing for donor contributions and project payouts.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Mobile/PWA support for community and project field updates.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Ensuring legitimacy and preventing “greenwashing” in project validation.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Designing fair benefit-sharing for local and Indigenous communities, including rights and consent.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Aligning with evolving international carbon standards and reporting requirements.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-30 14:27:14</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>bbc8a29393b0321097a53d6efaba10d4</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Carbon Offset &amp; Nature Conservation Marketplace</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_bbc8a29393b0321097a53d6efaba10d4</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-30 14:27:15</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
